JAYESH KOLI

M: +91-9820093166 Email: jayeshkoli@gmail.com

FINANCE OPERATIONS, MIS, INTERCOMPANY RECONCILIATION, FINANCIAL PLANNING AND ANALYSIS PROFESSIONAL

A result oriented Finance professional with over 18 years of experience in the field of Financial Planning and Analysis with specialization in Financial Analysis, Budgeting, Forecasting, MIS, Intercompany reconciliations and General Ledger Analysis helping me sharpen my Finance skills to provide valuable inputs for the organization.

Objective is to seek a challenging position in a growing organization with an opportunity of continuous advancement.

EDUCATION:

- Cert in Business Accounting from Chartered Institute of Management Accountants UK April'2013
- Bachelor of Commerce, Mumbai University April'1999
- Pursuing CGMA from Chartered Institute of Management Accountants UK.

TECHNOLOGY SUMMARY:

Accounting Tools: SAP, Hyperion Financial Module, SharePoint and PeopleSoft Financials.

Analytics Tools : Shibumi, Axiom, Business Objects Web-i, COGNOS, IEX, Symposium, QlikView.

Other Software : Word, Excel, Power-Point, Outlook and Lotus notes.

KEY SKILLS

Team Management
 Intercompany Reconciliation
 Stakeholder Management
 Project Management
 Management Reporting
 Stakeholder Management
 Process Migration
 Expense reporting
 Variance Analysis

EMPLOYMENT SUMMARY:

- Capita India Services Pvt. Ltd. (July 2018 Till Date) Deputy Manager Group Investment Reporting
 - Leading a team of analysts responsible for Group-wide Investment Reporting that includes Capita's Divisional level Capital Expenditure spend against annual budget / forecast and challenging each division on under / over capex spend.
 - Responsible for group level reporting of all Restructuring related investment spend with comparison given to budget and forecast, accrual and tracking of new Cost to Achieve Column 2 items and monthly Cash flow of transformation programs.
 - Preparations of Monthly Restructuring Forecast Review Deck with latest outturn numbers and follow up discussion with Group Chief Transformation Officer / Investment Director.
 - Provide support to Group Investment Director in formalizing plan / variance reporting on various Capex projects across the group and also to produce monthly Capex Board report for the management.
 - Challenging divisions on actual spent on capex projects which are beyond threshold and not yet approved by Capita Investment Review committee.
 - Project Lead on newly developed Capex Reporting Tool (Customized Shibumi Platform) built for tracking of all capex projects.
 - Consistent delivery on SLAs and Adhoc reports resulting in additional FTE approval by Onshore for the India team.
- Credit Suisse India Services Pvt. Ltd. (Feb 2016 Oct 2017) (ENO Group Finance)
 - Analyzing monthly reconciliation gap report and co-coordinating with various CS legal entities to identify the reason for the break.
 - Liaising with stakeholders / counterparts to eliminate reconciliation gaps, with auditors from controls perspective and Product Controllers / Business Controllers.
 - Perform analytical review of the process on a monthly basis and preparation of governance packs and MIS reports
 - Monthly Expense Analysis, Management Reporting, FTE analysis for Adverse / Favorable trending of recharges and variance analysis for deviations from Forecasts.

- Active participation in various process wise project initiatives related to process standardization, improvements which aimed at various types of cost savings.
- Prudential Global Services (Sept 2006 to April 2015) Manager Commercial Finance (Financial Planning and Performance Analysis)
 - Project transition from onsite to offshore location and business continuity.
 - Monthly Expense Analysis, Management Reporting, FTE analysis, variance analysis.
 - Analyzing, investigating key movements and trends in major Sales & Expenses Reporting.
 - Identify opportunities to migrate various kind of MIS / analytical work from UK to Mumbai.
 - Working with Finance Business Partners to deliver on annual budgeting, quarterly forecasts.
 - Review with management on potential process related risks and ensure such risks and their mitigation measures
 are incorporated into forecasts.
 - Facilitate benchmarking and sharing of best practices across the Business Line.
 - Identify talent for projects, mentoring people at various levels, conduct knowledge sharing sessions, driving career development plan for team members and mentees from other departments.
- Intelenet Global Services (Nov 2004 to Sept 2006, including a period of Nov'04 to Feb'06 with Countrywide Financial Corporate as a part of Barclay's process) Team Lead MIS (Barclay's Mortgage Lending Services)
 - Publishing periodic MIS of daily Operations.
 - FTE planning by call forecasting using historical data.
 - Developing Staffing Models across Business Unit.
 - Monthly Performance Score Card & KPI reports on exceptions.
 - Designing Formats, Dashboard Reports for Leadership / Operations Team & development of Standard Templates for Transaction Monitoring.
 - Monitoring the processes closely for performance across all billable matrices, SLAs & Service Matrices.
 - Closely monitor the thresholds set for all service impacting parameters.
- First Source Ltd. Erstwhile ICICI One Source (Aug 2003 to Oct 2004) Process Analyst
 - Managed MIS for Voice (Inbound/Outbound), Data (Email/Correspondence) & Collections processes.
 - Maintained MIS for all KPI's for all functions (Client and Internal SLA's, Key Ops Metrics such as agent utilization, downtime, billing, attrition & absenteeism).
 - Preparation of Daily, Weekly and Monthly Dashboards for Clients and internal customers using Symposium / Avaya / Citrix& Client Servers.
 - Providing inputs to the Finance team for preparation of Billing invoices for all processes.
 - Trend Analysis of areas of improvement & Documentation.
 - Generation of Key Operational Metrics for all newly migrated processes from day 1 of Go-Live.
 - Revenue, Profit/Loss analysis, Cost inputs to Realization of revenue & Seat Capacity planning.
 - Part of the Work Force management Team (WFM) Rostering, Break Management & maintaining Attendance Tracker.
- TracMail India Services (Nov 2000 to July 2003) & Jay Instruments and Systems Pvt. Ltd. (Nov 1999 to May 2000)
 - Briefly worked in Operations department providing online & telephonic customer support to various US based customers. Maintained MIS for all KPI's for all functions (Client and Internal SLA's, Key Ops Metrics such as agent utilization, downtime, billing, attrition & absenteeism).

PERSONAL DETAILS

- Address: Flat No.-1703, Tower 2, Swastik Regalia, Waghbil, Off GB Road, Thane(w), Mumbai -400615
- DOB: 13th June 1979